(upbeat music)
- Hello English learners,
welcome back to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
- And I'm Erika.
- And today we're back in the office.
We have a lesson that's talking about
something that goes wrong in the office.
- Yes, something that I can really understand
well, but we'll talk about that later.
So this lesson is about a photocopier.
- A photocopier.
So let's take a look at this
word in vocabulary preview.
- Very vocabulary preview.
- All right, so a photocopier makes copies.
Yeah, it makes copies of documents.
We often call it a
copier or a copy machine.
Yeah, so you can call it a
photocopier, copy machine, or a copier.
- Yes, or a Xerox machine as well.
- Xerox machine, yeah.
We can talk about that a little bit later
'cause that's an interesting story, okay?
All right, let's take a
look at our next word.
Toner.
- Toner.
So Toner is what the copy
machine uses to make copies.
- It's like the ink, right?
- It's a very fine black powder.
- Oh.
- Yeah, yeah.
- So it's not an ink.
- No, it's actually dry.
- Okay.
- Yeah, yeah, it's dry, it's a powder so
you don't wanna get that all over you.
- All right, well good advice, Marco.
And our last word in
vocabulary preview, malfunction.
- Mouth, function.
- Let's break down this word.
- All right, function.
- To work, uh-huh.
- All right.
- Mouth.
- I guess mouth maybe comes
from Latin or something 'cause
in Spanish we say malle which
is something evil or not good.
- Okay, so I think we can understand
malle function is not good working, right?
(laughing)
- Yeah, okay, more or less.
It's not working properly.
- Not working properly, right?
- Okay, well why don't
we listen to the dialogue
and find out what
isn't working properly?
(upbeat music)
- Hey Carl, can you make a copy
of this contract for me please?
And when you have it ready,
send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
- Sure.
(phone ringing)
- I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
- Yeah, sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
When you're way up, can you
fax this while I try and fix this thing?
- Sure.
(phone ringing)
Damn it, everything in this
office seems to be breaking down.
I'll send the stupid fax later.
(phone ringing)
- Oh great, is someone
playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
- The elevator has some sort of
mouth function to stick the stairs to you.
Well, Thor, are you going to it?
- I have to go up 15 floors.
- Never mind.
(sighs)
- Made it.
- There's a copier.
(phone ringing)
- No!
- Okay, so this copy machine is
definitely not working properly.
- A serious mouth function,
a serious mouth function.
I think the whole building exploded.
- All right, very dramatic here at
English pod, but we have fun, right?
- Exactly.
- Okay, let's take a
look at some of the great
language that we saw
in language takeaway.
- Language takeaway.
- All right, three words for
you here in language takeaway.
And we heard all of these in the dialogue.
So this guy needs to get a copy ASAP.
- ASAP.
- Or ASAP.
- Yes.
- Meaning as soon as possible.
- So really, really fast.
- Really fast.
- Yeah, this is a very, very
common phrase, right?
- So it's an acronym and
you can say it like ASAP or?
- ASAP, exactly.
- Yeah, usually people
say it like that because
it's too long, I guess, to
say as soon as possible.
So hey, I need this document ASAP.
- Yes.
- Or ASAP.
- Exactly.
Okay, let's look at our next word.
A practical joke.
- Practical joke.
- Okay, so a practical joke.
I'm sure we have all played a practical
joke on some of our friends, right?
- Yes.
- Basically what you do is you do
something funny on purpose to someone.
- Yeah, but something crazy.
- Crazy, right?
- Yeah.
- For example, when I was in
university, there was this guy
in our building and we took
all of his bedroom furniture.
So his bed, his desk, everything,
and put it down on the football field.
- Nice.
- Yeah, that was a practical joke.
- That is a very good and
elaborate practical joke.
- Yep.
- Okay, so practical joke, do
something crazier funny to your friends.
- Mm-hmm.
- Okay, and now let's
look at our last word.
Never mind.
- Never mind.
- Okay, so if you say never mind,
it means-- - Don't worry about it.
- Don't worry about it.
- Forget it.
- Never mind.
- Yep.
- Yeah, this is so, you
know, this is so common
and I think it would be helpful
to understand how it's used.
So let's hear some examples.
- Example one.
Someone stole my wallet.
- Oh, wait, never mind.
Here it is.
- Example two.
- Can you get some milk on your way home?
Oh, never mind.
We still have some.
- Example three.
- The printer's broken?
- Never mind.
I'll do this later.
- Okay, great examples.
And I think our language takeaway is clear.
So why don't we listen to our
dialogue for the second time
and then we'll come back and
talk about putting it together.
(upbeat music)
- Hey Carl, can you make a copy
of this contract for me please?
And when you have it ready,
send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
- Sure, I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
- Yeah, sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
On your way up, can you fax
this while I try and fix this thing?
- Sure, damn it.
Everything in this office
seems to be breaking down.
I'll send the stupid fax later.
- Oh great, is someone
playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
- The elevator has some
sort of mouth function
to take the stairs to you.
- Well, Thor, are you going to?
- I have to go up 15 floors.
Never mind.
Made it.
There's a cop here.
- No!
- In this dialogue, there's
some great language
that can be used in many different
patterns or in many different ways.
So in today's putting it together,
we're going to show you how
to use three of these patterns.
- Putting it together.
- Okay, the first pattern that we can
look at is out of toner, out of toner.
- Right, so we already talked about toner.
- Yep, let's talk about out of.
- Okay, so when you
are out of, you have none.
- Right, so let's change a little
bit so I can say, I am out of milk.
- Uh huh, I'm out of time.
- Out of time, right?
If you're driving, I'm
out of gas or gasoline.
- Yep, so out of plus noun.
- Perfect, it means you don't have none.
- You don't have none.
- Englishpod.com.
- You ain't got none.
- Ubonics.com, all right, out of time.
Let's take a look at our
second one, on your way up.
- Yeah, on your way up.
- On your way, right?
So this is a great way when you are talking
to someone and they are going somewhere.
- Yes, right?
- So on your way up,
can you bring this to HR?
- Okay, on your way to the store.
- Can you mail this letter or
maybe on your way home?
- Can you buy me some flowers?
(laughs) - Nice, all
right, so on your way,
it means, it means
while you are going there.
- Right, yeah.
- Taking advantage of the fact
that you are going somewhere.
- Yes.
- Okay, now let's take
a look at our last one
and this is a really great
phrase, break down.
- Break down.
- In our dialogue, we heard breaking down.
- Yes.
- Everything in the office
seems to be breaking down.
- Right, so when something
breaks down, it stops working.
- It stops working, exactly.
So we can change it a little bit.
What happens if we say break up?
- Ooh, boyfriend and girlfriend.
- Right.
- They end their relationship.
- Okay, so we can maybe think about
it as their relationship stops working.
- Oh, nice one, right?
- Yeah.
- Okay, what about break in?
- Mm, enter a place using force.
- Right, you enter a
house that's not yours.
- Yeah, so if you break into a house,
maybe you break the window and climb in.
- Okay, what about break out?
- The opposites, right?
- So for example, you
might break out of jail.
- Break out of prison, yep.
- So this is a great phrase.
You can change the last
word from break down,
break up, break in and
it means different things.
- Yeah, so use different
prepositions for different meanings.
- Perfect.
- Okay, so now let's listen to our dialogue
for the last time and then
Erica and I will be back
and talk a little bit more about
mouth functioning office supplies.
(upbeat music)
- Hey, Carl, can you make a copy
of this contract for me, please?
And when you have it ready,
send it out ASAP to our sub branch.
- Sure.
(phone ringing)
- I think I broke this thing.
Maxine, can you help me out here?
I'm not really a tech guy.
- Yeah, sure.
I think it's just out of toner.
You can go use the other one upstairs.
On your way up, can you fax
this while I try and fix this thing?
- Sure.
(phone ringing)
Damn it, everything in this
office seems to be breaking down.
I'll send the stupid fax later.
Oh great, is someone
playing a practical joke on me?
This is ridiculous.
- The elevator has some sort of
mouth function to take the stairs to you.
Well, sorry, are you going to?
- I have to go up 15 floors.
Never mind.
(sighing)
- Made it.
There's a copier.
(phone ringing)
- No!
- All right, so Erica,
everything that you touch
that's electronic seems
to mouth function, right?
- This is absolutely true.
I don't know what it is, but you know what,
if I turn on a computer,
it will suddenly get a virus.
And even if I'm very
careful, it still breaks.
- Right, yeah, it happens sometimes.
I can relate to that, but you are much
better at computers and technology than I am.
- Well, I really, really like them.
And well, I guess even I know a little bit
about copy machines or copiers because my
uncles are like copy technicians, really.
- Yeah, so, you know, they
fix copiers that broke down
or they replace toner and,
you know, they do all that stuff.
So that's why I know a little bit about it.
But actually the original
term is a Xerox machine.
- Yes, why is that from the brand, right?
- Ah, right.
- There's a brand called Xerox and Xerox
invented and patent this
technology of making copies.
- All right, well, the
next time my photocopier
explodes, I'll call you,
calm my uncle, right?
(laughing)
All right, and well, let us know
how things in your office break down
or if you have any stories of like
Erica that breaks everything she catches.
- It's true.
- All right, so come to our website,
come to our comment
section and leave your opinions
and we'll be there to also answer any
doubts or questions you might have.
- That's right, you can
find us at EnglishPod.
com and Mark and
I are always around.
- All right, so we'll see you guys there.
- Yeah, we will.
(laughing) Okay guys, thanks
for listening and until next time.
- Bye. - Bye.
(upbeat music)